Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
Perturbed by the thoughts on my mind
no matter how hard I try to sever my love.
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
I bow in respect before Your Majesty.
Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
Rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
I haven't seen you two arrive together in a long time.
If only everyone in the palace could be
as harmonious as you two.
Sourire and I have always been harmonious sisters.
Because the weather is getting hotter,
His Majesty is planning to escape
the heat in the Summer Palace.
We will depart in a few days.
You should organize who and what
you want to bring with you beforehand.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
The Empress Dowager has not been able to
leave the palace since she became ill.
I would like to stay and attend Her Majesty.
I will fulfill my filial piety to
Her Majesty through attentive service.
I appreciate your filial thoughts.
I thank Your Majesty.
The Imperial Household Department has
arranged everything as before.
His Majesty stays in The Peaceful Nine States.
Her Majesty stays in Peach Blossoms Haven.
Your Highness stays in Verdant Reading Hall.
Doesn’t Noble Lady An stay in Lush Blossoms Chamber?
Why did she walk that way?
Your Highness,
Lady An will live in Leisured Moon Chamber.
His Majesty says that
Lady An is close to Your Highness, so your residences
should be nearby so that you can take care of each other.
It is also near to His Majesty.
I have something else to attend to.
I will visit Lady An another time.
You may leave.
I bid Your Highness goodbye.
My Lady,
are you feeling sad about Lady Vertu?
Last year, Meizhuang was in the prime of His Majesty's favor.
But this year, Lingrong stays in Leisured Moon Chamber.
Household items remain the same, but occupants change.
I fear that once I go there,
it will sadden me.
It's kind of you to feel this way.
But you should understand, My Lady,
there are many concubines in the palace.
One may be favored today, and another one tomorrow.
It is not certain.
You care about Lady Vertu,
but you don’t need to feel sad about her.
Jinxi.
I always worry too much over such trifles.
My Lady, you are sentimental sometimes.
However,
only a kind and gentle person would feel this way.
Cruel people would never.
Your shortcoming is that you are too soft-hearted.
You have so much to care about.
Your Highness!
Fourth Prince, come down! Come down here!
Be careful not to fall.
Come down here.
Peace to Your Highness.
Why did you climb up so high?
Aren't you afraid of falling?
Except for my maids, no one cares about me.
Silly boy!
I heard that Father came here, and
I want to pay my respects to him.
But I'm scared that he doesn’t want to see me.
So I climbed up on the rocks
hoping that I would see him.
You want to see your father?
I will bring you to visit him.
But today,
His Majesty is meeting officials in court.
I’m afraid he won’t finish anytime soon.
Why don't you go back?
When His Majesty is available,
I will take you to him.
All right?
I thank Your Highness!
I'll be happy just to see Father.
Go on.
Here, Your Highness, this is for you.
Your Majesty,
Nian Gengyao took advantage of military
actions to claim false merits,
and secretly accepted bribes to arrange
high-ranking posts for his subordinates.
His subordinates leaned on his power to act with impunity.
Nian Gengyao's household servant Wei Zhiyao
has been exceedingly arrogant.
When he came to Beijing,
all civil officials bowed to him
and all military officers knelt.
But Wei Zhiyao passed by sitting on his sedan
without even looking at them.
This demonstrates his arrogance and feelings of power.
Your Majesty,
Nian Gengyao exercises dominance over all the officials.
On the pretext of training the military,
he detains many children of officials in his encampment.
After Wang Yun, the General of North Sichuan retired,
Nian Gengyao ordered his son to serve in his own regiment:
requested in the name of service,
but truly held as a hostage.
This is how he forces officials to obey him.
Enough.
This matter is of paramount significance.
Let's end it here today.
Inform Zhang Tingyu and Longkodo to see me tomorrow.
You may leave.
I thank Your Majesty.
Your Highness.
Where is His Majesty?
His Majesty says that he is unable to dine with Your Highness.
Please dine without him.
What’s more,
His Majesty said he anticipates being very busy
and might not be able to accompany Your Highness.
Allow me to take my leave.
Stay away!
I carefully inquired of His Majesty's servants.
It turns out that Zhen Yuandao led an impeachment
against my brother and his subordinates.
His Majesty has ordered the Ministry of Justice
to seize the hundreds of thousands of taels
embezzled by Wei Zhiyao.
His Majesty said he gained his wealth
only because of his master
and that my brother abused his position to fill his own pockets,
which overflowed into those of his subordinates.
His Majesty despises corruption most of all.
Why were they so careless as to provoke His Majesty?
Zhen Yuandao's mouth never stops causing trouble.
He wants to help his daughter, and so he is against me.
I don’t know whether His Majesty
will also turn his anger on my brother.
These are small matters among some subordinates.
General Nian surely wasn’t involved.
Formerly there were some brazen fools who
tried to impeach General Nian,
but they were all rebuked by His Majesty.
His Majesty always trusted my brother
and rebuked those who reprimanded him.
But this time His Majesty has sent people to investigate
whether my brother knew of Wei Zhiyao's corruption.
Does His Majesty suspect my brother?
Your Highness,
It is only normal that His Majesty inquires.
But my brother’s subordinates tried to
cover up for Wei Zhiyao.
How could they?
Now His Majesty thinks that my brother’s
subordinates formed a faction to shield one another.
That’s why His Majesty sends people to investigate.
No wonder …
No wonder why His Majesty doesn’t come these days.
I’m afraid he's also turned his anger on me.
Don’t be sad, Your Highness.
It is difficult for Your Highness to see His Majesty right now.
In the future, Your Highness should refrain
from speaking about the Great General.
What can I do now?
Everyone can speak about it,
everyone but me.
Your Highness,
I think, the plan for now,
is to avoid making His Majesty angry with Your Highness.
Then, let Lady Cao speak for me.
It's not appropriate.
Noble Lady Cao is never in high favor with His Majesty.
She is also not at the center of His Majesty's heart.
I'm afraid ...
it's not appropriate for her to speak up.
If I can't speak for myself,
I will need someone to gain favor from His Majesty
and speak for me.
Your Majesty,
the missteps of Wei Zhiyao are small
compared to other matters.
My investigation clearly shows
Nian Gengyao used his family to seek
exorbitant profits through business.
Nian Gengyao's sons,
Nian Fu and Nian Bin,
falsified documents to take ownership of salt pools.
They have made a profit of more than one hundred seventy thousand taels in the last two years.
This is only "one hair of a bull's back"
compared to what they have done.
As Qing Dynasty's law prescribes,
generals and governors should communicate
in the format of a Counsel Letter.
But, without permission, Nian Gengyao sends Command Orders
to his subordinate generals and governors
in the tone of an emperor.
Nian Gengyao endowed publishing
"Sir Lu Zhi's Memorials to Emperor Dezong"
and entreated Your Majesty to write a preface for the book.
However, several days ago,
on the pretext of saving Your Majesty the bother,
he wrote the preface himself
and published it to the people.
"For any officials under a monarch,
it’s easy to seek merit
but hard to achieve it.
Once achieved,
even harder to maintain it;
And if merit is maintained,
it is harder still to maintain it to the end.”
Moreover, if they err because of pride in their merits,
former favor will become disfavor.
These are all common feelings of men.
Send this to all.
Let him reflect on it.
Your Majesty,
Nian Gengyao's arrogant behavior
is an audacious act of rebellion against Your Majesty.
Nian Gengyao was one of my retainers.
He contributed much
to my accession and governance.
I don't
wish to cut off my relation with him.
Your Majesty,
it's time for noon tea.
Serve it.
Your Majesty, this is the latest Longjing tea.
Please have a taste.
Quiet.
You were not spoken to.
I beg Your Majesty's pardon.
Song Zhi ...
It's you.
I obey Her Highness Consort Flour's order
to serve Your Majesty the tea.
This dress looks nice on you.
Allow me to take my leave.
Proceed.
You said that Consort Flour sent you here.
Peace to Your Highness.
Greetings, ministers.
You may rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, please have the tea.
Your Highness.
Your Highness,
it's been a while.
I believe Song Zhi will stay here today.
Your Highness can leave if you wish.
Thank you, Mr. Su.
Your Highness has a keen eye for beauty.
That's why His Majesty appreciates Song Zhi.
Your Highness, you haven't slept yet?
In the past, Lady Cao and Concubine Beauté
were seeking my support
and I aided in their promotion.
But to send a woman to His Majesty's bed ...
It's the first time.
Your Highness had your reasons to do so.
How I wish Song Zhi would come back
and tell me that His Majesty didn't like her
so she was told to leave.
But if that happens,
it's not good for the greater plan.
Go out.
I appreciate your service.
I dare not forget my position.
Speaking of your position,
I cannot make you feel aggrieved.
You are Consort Fleur's maid,
so I need to treat you generously.
I will make an exception and
grant you the rank of Companion,
instead of starting from Escort.
I thank Your Majesty.
Remember to kowtow to Consort Flour.
She was your master after all.
You should thank her for promoting you.
Yes.
Your Highness,
I've tested - the water temperature is comfortable.
I've added the rose extract.
Please allow me to serve
Your Highness as you wash your face.
You are back.
Did His Majesty
give you the rank of Escort?
His Majesty holds Your Highness in great esteem
and so, granted me
the rank of Companion.
That is quite an honor.
I assume that His Majesty ...
likes you very much.
The only reason I was promoted is that Your Highness
holds a prominent place in His Majesty's heart.
His Majesty told me that
I am Your Highness's servant
so he wouldn't treat me humbly.
All right.
You are a concubine now.
From now on,
stop calling yourself a servant.
Where did His Majesty assign you to live?
His Majesty said,
since I have always lived with Your Highness,
I will continue living with Your Highness.
His Majesty bestowed grace upon me
only because Your Highness promoted me.
Whether I am a maid or concubine,
I will always be Your Highness's servant.
Rise.
You received favor and didn't forget your origins.
I will treat you like a sister of mine.
Inform Zhou Ninghai to clean the west chamber,
and select two maids to serve you.
I am grateful to Your Highness.
Go and take some rest.
I will have someone else serve me.
I am accustomed to serving Your Highness.
Please let me help Your Highness get ready.
I appreciate your thoughts.
- Su Peisheng.
- Your Majesty.
I will not visit the Empress.
Yes.
Would Your Majesty like to dine in Jiuzhou Qingyan or ...
I'll dine with Consort Fleur.
To the Cooling Hall.
Do you think my mood is fickle?
Your Majesty is the monarch of the country.
You can go where you want to
and we will follow.
It has been long since last time I visited her.
Her Highness has cultivated her virtues.
She wants me to see her virtues,
then I will have a look.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Your Majesty has not come for some time.
I've been occupied with the issues in court.
You have to understand.
Companion Zhi, take a seat.
I am honored to serve Your Majesty and Your Highness.
Please allow me to do so.
We are a family.
Seeing you stand makes me ill at ease.
Since Companion Zhi is being modest,
you should allow her to.
I remember you prefer utensils
decorated with gold leaf.
My brother sent this set to me.
He said it's simple and elegant.
I'm glad that he appreciates simplicity.
My brother often says
"Wealth is a rarity and must not be squandered."
My brother holds a high post.
He is also deeply honored by Your Majesty's grace.
It's inevitable that some would
defame him out of jealousy.
Consort Fleur,
I know what is proper in governance of the state.
You have been serving me all these years.
You should understand
which matters you can comment on
and which you cannot.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty has finished.
Perhaps,
Companion Zhi can accompany Your Majesty to rest?
Very well.
I am pretty tired, myself.
I'll go to Companion Zhi's chamber.
Yes, Your Majesty.
There's nothing wrong with Consort Fleur
presenting concubines to His Majesty.
But why did she choose her maid?
Consort Fleur was afraid to lose favor again.
In fact,
after losing Concubine Beauté,
she wanted to foster new concubines.
But she didn't want a lady from a distinguished family.
She feared she would lose control
if they gained too much favor.
So she selected Song Zhi.
At least Consort Fleur knows her thoroughly.
Can Song Zhi become a powerful instrument?
Did you ever pay attention to her?
Does Your Highness wish to hear the truth?
Consort Fluer made an impetuous decision.
Why do you say that?
Song Zhi does have her cleverness
and a pretty face.
But she is so afraid of and obedient to Consort Fleur.
that she can't pose any threat.
Consort Fleur wanted Song Zhi
to share His Majesty's favor
from Your Highness and Lady An.
It's not a sensible decision.
I never thought that Song Zhi could contend against me.
It appears that all Consort Fleur's tricks
have been exhausted.
In the past,
Consort Fleur would never allow
any maids to get close to His Majesty.
But today, she ...
Even she knows that
today is different from the past.
Of course.
Your Highness's father
led the impeachment of Nian Gengyao and his servants
hitting him where it hurts most.
Your Majesty,
This morning His Majesty promoted one of Consort Fleur's maids ...
to Companion.
Maids should be promoted to Escort first.
Why didn't His Majesty tell me when she served him?
She served His Majesty last night.
I consider it against the imperial rules.
It is the emperors who made the rules.
There hasn't been a new concubine for a long time.
Let it be.
What are you doing?
Comb my hair carefully!
The weather is so hot.
Fortunately, Her Highness has invited us to the opera house.
It‘s His Majesty who remembered
that we enjoy watching operas.
It's already so hot in the morning.
It will be intolerable by the afternoon.
You cannot stand the heat, My Lady.
You can bathe first thing when ...
Peace to Your Highness.
Rise.
Have you ever imagined ...
the day I have my status restored?
Your Highness has unending blessings from Heaven.
I do not question the divine.
I haven't congratulated Your Highness
on your reinstatement.
I extend my congratulations.
No need.
I do not merit your congratulations.
The more obediently you behave,
the more detestable you are.
Your highness is bantering.
Does Your Highness prefer me to be defiant
and speak disrespectfully to Your Highness?
I dare not offend Your Highness.
But you have already.
I will never forget what happened in the past.
I appreciate Your Highness's advice.
I am always willing to listen to
Your Highness's teachings.
You are always willing
but I don’t want to often see your face.
Your Highness, please don’t be angry.
Your Highness's precious health
is not worth being harmed by a trivial concubine.
Status and rank are the natural order.
Why should a noble person be angry with a humble person?
Wouldn't that be an honor to the humble?
You ...
Isn't this Song Zhi who has
newly gained favor from His Majesty?
What you just said is true.
"Status and rank are the natural order."
You spoke with such confidence
that it is a shame
that you’re just a humble Companion.
I must suggest to His Majesty
that he grant you the rank of Concubine or Noble Lady
to recognize your nobleness.
Your Highness,
His Majesty invited us to the opera house.
I’ve heard that
His Majesty specially ordered Your Highness's
favorite play, The Niangzi Pass.
Why bother wasting time
under the scorching sun?
Vermilion, let’s go.
It was getting hot outside and you hadn’t come back.
I was about to send someone to look.
I was just walking around in the garden.
What can happen?
Jade, I was furious.
We ran into Consort Fleur and Companion Zhi.
My Lady suffered a great grievance.
What happened?
My Lady is in high favor right now.
How could they not be fearful of behaving rudely?
Consort Fleur always treats My Lady like that.
But Companion Zhi is intolerable!
She was just a maid.
How dare she "speak with barbs"!
She was Consort Fleur’s servant.
Naturally, she has became a jackal relying on a tiger.
My Lady, you were being too kind.
We can ignore Consort Fleur,
but do we need to tolerate Song Zhi?
If I were you,
I would slap her so sharply
and tell His Majesty to banish her to the slave caste.
Just listen to Vermillion -
her tongue has become so unsparing.
It seems that she is in charge of my palace.
Your temper is too short.
Can that accomplsh anything for me?
I told you both:
don't cause conflicts with Confort Fleur.
Now one more rule:
don't cause conflicts with her subjects.
Pay no attention to them.
There is ample time ahead for us.
But Song Zhi treated you so impertinently,
do you forgive her, My Lady?
Jade, what do you think?
My Lady,
I believe it's better to endure this momentarily
for future revenge.
Forbearance is a must at the moment.
Besides, I disdain taking action against someone like Song Zhi.
Enduring her now
doesn't mean I will not act in the future.
Song Zhi dares to be so arrogant
because she has Consort Fleur behind her.
Do you really think her capable of anything?
She's just a small pawn.
My Lady, you mean…
What is written in Du Fu’s
sixth poem in “Out of the Frontier”?
"To capture an army, shoot their horses.
And to take down an enemy, ..."
"eliminate their ruler!"
I have read
all these memorandums are to impeach Nian Gengyao.
I have marked and commented on each of them.
Yes.
I await Your Majesty's adjudication.
Nian Gengyao acts arrogantly
and naturally the other officials resent him.
I
as the Emperor
must listen to the officials and the people.
Naturally, I want them
to be able to speak freely.
Zhen Yuandao.
Your Majesty.
Those who are able to speak -
make sure they open their mouths to you.
Yes, My Majesty.
Two days ago,
I asked Nian Gengyao about something important.
Of course,
I also want to hear your opinions.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Lord VIII Yunsi and Lord IX Yuntang
[the Emperor's brothers]
have long been imprisioned in Imperial Clan Court.
I've heard they not only didn't reflect on their faults
but also cursed me, and the prior emperor.
What do you think I should do?
The guilty officials Yunsi and Yuntang
formed a faction and acted unlawfully.
If they refuse to be repentant,
that is an unforgivable crime.
Uncle, what do you think?
Your Majesty, although Yunsi and Yuntang are guilty,
they are, after all,
Your Majesty's brothers.
What about sending respected senior members of
the clan to enlighten them in Imperial Clan Court?
Zhen Yuandao.
Your Majesty, if they dare to ignore
the relations of monarch and subject
as Your Majesty's brothers,
or if they formerly failed to fulfil the duties between brothers
and refuse to repent and amend their faults,
then Your Majesty need not grant any favors beyond the laws.
All your comments are reasoned.
I will think it over.
His Majesty asked my brother
what to do about Yunsi and Yuntang.
What do you think?
The great general has been repeatedly impugned recently,
and His Majesty ...
expressed approval of the accusers.
I'm afraid the general might be uneasy about this,
and fearful of offending His Majesty
with an improper response.
So at this juncture,
he must be careful how he answers His Majesty.
Yes.
If His Majesty
shows no mercy towards
his brothers Yunsi and Yuntang,
what would happen if my brother was slandered in the future?
Would His Majesty be even more ruthless?
Your Highness is having unnecessary concerns.
Why would His Majesty do this to the great general?
There have been so many people speaking against my brother lately.
Even among the people surrounding my brother -
some ingrates have appeared.
His Majesty asked my brother
such a question in this situation ...
What does he really mean?
Perhaps...
Perhaps His Majesty just asked casually, that's all.
No chance.
His Majesty is never like that.
His Majesty always thought highly of my brother.
But now, begins to doubt my brother.
The Nians are always loyal and devoted to His Majesty.
Yes.
His Majesty must be confused by the rumors.
His Majesty is not a person who
feels no affection for the past.
If Your Highness is afraid that
"teeth will feel cold when the lips are gone",
Your Highness could ask the great general
to talk more about etiquette and filial piety
in front of His Majesty
in order to appeal to His Majesty emotionally.
This will remind His Majesty
of the great general's loyalty
and create gratitude for his military merits.
But Yunsi and Yuntang fought against
His Majesty for the throne
and intended to destabilize His Majesty's authority.
They are
the ones His Majesty hates and detests the most.
Is it all right to reply this way?
Of course,
the great general should not advise
His Majesty to release Yunsi and Yuntang.
However,
there is no harm in mentioning their
decades of devotion as brothers.
And at the same time, asserting his own loyalty to His Majesty.
I believe such a reply would be fine.
This is not a bad concession.
His Majesty is soft-hearted and affectionate towards the past
with Your Highness,
and even more so with the great general.
You are the most carefree in the palace.
Grace to Your Majesty.
I have nothing to do. I'm just being lazy.
Did His Majesty come from the Governance Hall?
Consort Fleur just came to me.
To speak for General Nian?
She came to speak about you.
Of course, I know you have done your best to tolerate it.
Your Majesty won't believe in what she said, right?
I won't.
Consort Fleur told me that you were disrespectful to her.
She also brought Companion Zhi
who was crying endlessly.
It's her nature to be strong-willed and
she never stops until she reaches her goal.
What does Your Majesty intend to do about it?
I have to make this move against my will.
I don't want you to hear these
disturbing things and worry about me.
I tell you only that
Nian Gengyao is getting more and more presumptuous.
I have no more tolerance for it.
Your Majesty is the Son of Heaven.
You're capable of doing anything.
Since the knife has been in your heart for a long time,
it's time to remove it.
I have refrained until this moment
in order to remove it smoothly.
If you were me, would you do the same?
Yes, I understand Your Majesty.
Good.
It's still early, I'll go back to read the memorandum.
You can have some rest.
I bid Your Majesty goodbye.
Tomorrow,
I will host a banquet in Jiuzhou Qingyan.
Go there early.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Highness,
tonight, His Majesty selected
the name tag of Companion Zhi again.
You can go now.
Yes, Your Highness.
Did you hear that?
His Majesty is favoring Companion Zhi again.
Has it been any different in the past few days?
His Majesty has a new favorite.
He is only in the mood for her.
What kind of a new favorite is she?
She was just a humble servant before,
but now she's climbed into the dragon's bed.
It disgusts me
when I think about how she soils His Majesty's bed.
Sourire, you're being frank and outspoken.
I wouldn't dare to say this out loud.
I'm speaking the truth.
Since I dare to say it,
I'm not afraid of anyone spreading it.
Someday I will turn this "newly favored" to "out of favor".
Then she will learn her lesson.
Your Majesty,
I heard that you don’t like Great General Nian recently,
and have criticized his memorandums.
Who told you this?
I dare not listen to any gossip.
It's just because I live with Consort Fleur
and always hear such talk.
What are they talking about?
Do they say I'm unfaithful in my favors,
to rebuke a meritorious official?
Of course not.
They say that Great General Nian's conduct is improper,
which upsets Your Majesty.
I am angry because I think highly of Nian Gengyao.
I expect him to do everything well,
and not give others a reason to talk
and cause trouble for me.
So it's because Your Majesty cherishes the great general.
I cherish Consort Fleur and you.
Nian Gengyao contributed to the state.
And he's also my brother-in-law.
Consort Fleur has served me for years,
and she guides you to be sweet and well-behaved.
I hold it dearly in my heart.
Your Majesty.
My brother handed in a memorandum
following my suggestion.
His Majesty didn't say anything.
But His Majesty has stopped reprimanding my brother.
That's good. I feel relieved, too.
You have no idea.
I heard every day how His Majesty
reprimanded my brother in his memorandums.
It sent thousands of shivers through my heart.
Fortunately, Song Zhi has been serving His Majesty.
From His Majesty's tone,
she sounded out that
His Majesty still recognizes my brother's
great contributions to the nation.
Yes.
I can finally feel relieved.
His Majesty reprimanded the great general
only because of the base persons
seeking trouble from nothing.
His Majesty had to make a gesture.
How can His Majesty really reprimand the great general?
Your method worked fairly well.
As long as His Majesty sees the memorandum
and favors Your Highness more,
my mind will be at peace.
You are very conscientious.
As long as His Majesty favors me and my brother as before,
I won't treat you unfavorably.
On the day when Wenyi comes of age,
I will ask His Majesty to grant you the title of Concubine.
Your Highness, Companion Zhi has come back.
She wishes to pay her respects to Your Highness.
It's all right.
Let her take a rest first.
Yes, Your Highness.
Wait.
Don’t forget to reward her the ginseng soup.
Y..Yes, Your Highness.
Companion Zhi served His Majesty again last night.
With Your Highness's guidance,
Companion Zhi has certainly
gained high favor with His Majesty.
This is also her own good fortune.
You have my guidance just the same,
yet you are not favored as she is.
These few days, however,
a few gusts of wind blew into my ears.
I heard that Concubine Souire is very dissatisfied with
Companion Zhi's new-found favor.
I've also heard a bit about this from His Majesty.
No wonder His Majesty hasn't visited her recently.
Now I understand why.
His Majesty desires only Song Zhi.
Why would His Majesty want to hear
Concubine Souire's words soured with jealousy?
All right.
If she has been feeling sour,
I will
turn her favor sour to match.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Lonely Phoenix
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
I dimly recall the colorful blooms in every summer.
They are as distant as the autumn moon in the water.
He loved me with a volatile heart.
And before I knew it, we fell apart.
Behind me are the promises and longing.
Before me lie the flute and the zither.
I loved you with my body and soul
But you hurt me from head to toe.
My wish ran athwart
and I ended up a fool of my destiny.
My love was the wind-swept flowers from a tree.
A plum bloomed in winter hoping for a fruitful summer.
But the irresistible winds of destiny destroyed her wish.
You can hear the flapping of a phoenix
but you will never see it.
What you see is the falling leaves from the phoenix tree.
The falling leaves from the phoenix tree.